<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Loosely Coherent Ramblings</title><link>https://dave2.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Loosely Coherent Ramblings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:29:46 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dave2.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hexagon Game Update: The Past</title><link>https://dave2.github.io/post/hexagon-update-2022-10-13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:29:46 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://dave2.github.io/post/hexagon-update-2022-10-13/</guid><description>I realised that since I started writing this silly wee game I actually haven&amp;rsquo;t written down any of the initial thoughts about how this was goign to work, and since I&amp;rsquo;ve only just resurrected writing a blog after I&amp;rsquo;d already started writing the game there&amp;rsquo;s no history here either.
Right, let&amp;rsquo;s see about writing some of those thoughts down.
Hexagon tiles I&amp;rsquo;m implementing a classical RPG and hexagon tiles are pretty common for maps in that context.</description></item><item><title>Hexagon Game: Update for 12 October 2022</title><link>https://dave2.github.io/post/hexagon-update-2022-10-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:47:55 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://dave2.github.io/post/hexagon-update-2022-10-12/</guid><description>Well there&amp;rsquo;s been a little bit more progress on world generation. I&amp;rsquo;ve been avoiding working on roads (I have a theory) and rivers (lol no ideas), and doing &amp;ldquo;city&amp;rdquo; generation.
Placing the cities is easy enough. The world is divided into biomes, and we assign one city to each biome, checking to make sure when we place it there are no other cities too close. We also check against a reserved starting area.</description></item><item><title>Never Complete Games: Hexagon</title><link>https://dave2.github.io/post/never-complete-games-hexagon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 13:17:56 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://dave2.github.io/post/never-complete-games-hexagon/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s all this then? From time to time I get this idea I can and should write video games. Which usually doesn&amp;rsquo;t end well, but hey, it&amp;rsquo;s something which passes the time.
This round I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to go with a classic procedural RPG using hexagon tiles and a top-down perspective camera. I tried using an othrographic camera and yet again I ran into issues with how it was culling shapes close and far from the camera.</description></item><item><title>Wat Another Blog Again</title><link>https://dave2.github.io/post/wat-another-blog-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 12:55:42 +1300</pubDate><guid>https://dave2.github.io/post/wat-another-blog-again/</guid><description>What happened this time? Yep, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone and built yet another blog. This time I can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered hosting it on my own magic domain so for now it&amp;rsquo;s just in GitHub Pages.
It&amp;rsquo;s still Hugo? Yes, still based on Hugo. I have a real love for static site generation even if it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes a pain to work with. This time I&amp;rsquo;ve used some guide on using GH Actions to make this work, so I can just git push and stuff happens.</description></item></channel></rss>